[Music]
obviously the tree markets are quite
different right different in the sense
of uh population size for example
Singapore 5 over million Thailand 70
million Vietnam is close to about 100
million right so population size is
different as well as the history and the
depth of the insurance Market as well so
for credential we have been in Singapore
for a very long time so we have been in
Singapore for more than 90 over years um
but in Thailand we are now coming to
almost 30 years and in Vietnam 20 over
years so the Heritage the history is of
different depth in these markets for us
and uh at the same time the development
of the overall insurance industry and
the regulations as well so even though
these are all the differences in the
markets I also see commonality in the
tree markets right and it also maps to
the global trends that we are seeing so
for example people living longer right
uh advancement in health care in medical
science right therefore for people
living longer so I think these are all
the key trends that was see aging aging
population as well so from that
perspective while they are differences
there also commonality the commonality
will be huge protection Gap that we
continue to need to serve the the
community uh we look at um Saving right
savings for the individuals as well as
their families needs so it's not just
the protection and health but it's also
the financial well-being and the savings
for the long-term as
well specifically starting off with
Singapore Singapore went through a very
very resilient and strong performance uh
in the covid period so the preceding
three years last year
2023 uh there was a slight softening of
the entire Market here in Singapore and
I think the the result that was was a
result of a rapid increase in interest
rates as well as inflation m not
dissimilar to what we see in other
markets but here specifically in
Singapore we saw the entire industry
soften quite quickly especially in the
first half of last year down at the
industry level it was about
16.9% for throughout the entire life
insurance industry however we saw a very
quick Rebound in the second half of last
year and saw very strong quarter on
quarter growth so specifically speically
for presential Singapore that was what
our experience was and we saw a quick
pivot by our Distributors mainly our
bank Partners as well as our insurance
uh financial consultants um looking at
really rapidly growing the regular
premium business at the same time
protection and health business which has
always been the core focus of credential
Singapore being one of the very key uh
Shield players here in in in town as
well and also a pivot towards ILP MH
investment link policies so that that
also responded to the demands of the
customer so that that pivot help us
really see a very solid rebound and we
continue to see that kind momentum
carrying into this year of course last
year again right at the economic level
for the country Singapore we saw a very
soft GDP and with the forecasted GDP for
2024 this year which is going to be
higher than last year I think we
definitely can see the economic
activities um being more robust compared
to a year back over to Thailand Thailand
we continue to run a very strong
business we've been there like I
mentioned almost 30 years our business
model is predicated on serving our
customers primarily through the bank
Assurance Channel and traditionally we
have two very strong uh Bank partners
that we work with the ttb bank as well
as a UOB Thailand bank so these two have
been our anchor uh Channel and we
continue to really push out Health
protection savings solutions to the
customer base through the branch Network
and through their their customer base so
to speak we also work that through our
very uh Niche agency Force as well so
that has been the business model so last
year generally overall 2023 was a good
year for for Thailand and we continue to
maintain our number three position in
the bank Assurance market and happy to
to report that our local team has really
uh done really well and we now have also
signed up our third banking partner so
that is also from a company perspective
which happen to be which happen to be
CIMB Thailand yeah so that helps us
diversify our our overall approach from
a bank Assurance perspective so having
another new player in there that gives
us access to close to almost two more
million customers through their 54
Branch Network as well so that's
something that going into 2024 we we
really excited for the new opportunities
as we continue to build that business
and finally over to uh Vietnam Vietnam
again has been a fast growing Market
with huge potential uh with huge uh
protection and uh uh savings needs as
well and we saw that growth in the past
many years However unfortunately last
year we saw the entire softening of the
market at the industry level at the
country level and uh also a reduce
consumer confidence so that that that
has been the case so in short um um
while the market kind of
uh reduce overall we reduce a lot slower
compared to the average in the market
and in fact we even grew market share
and are now the market number one player
in the Vietnam Insurance Market the key
Focus for us now going into this year is
to continue to partner The Regulators
because the key thing is to really lift
the overall standards of the industry
[Music]
I think in the covid years and then now
of course so-called postco um there are
key lessons and key trends right covid
is it feels like so long ago but
actually it's also not that long ago
it's only in the recent years right but
what that experience taught all of us is
actually the importance of protection
people wanted to protect themselves
people wanted to protect their families
people were beginning to really look at
their financial planning look at their
protection plan right take it out dust
it off and I I I I think that was a very
good learning uh good outcome of course
I TR I I hope that we will not need
another pandemic of this kind of nature
to really remind everyone but so in
short I think that was the key learning
then and we continue to see that
behavior happening so so therefore as a
business we will continue to respond to
the markets needs the the community's
needs in terms of protection in terms of
uh healthare health insurance needs so
these would need continuous uh
innovation in products Innovation not
just products but Services as well to to
better serve the families second one is
postco right immediately postco we
started seeing some of the things
happening in the world a bit unfortunate
but these are the
realities we saw geopolitical tension MH
we saw the very unfortunate uh Ukraine
Russia War we saw Supply chains being
disrupted uh we saw rapid rise in
interest rates we saw fairly High
inflation so that that whole Mega Trend
in short I think to distill it down the
importance therefore to the consumer to
the public is actually the importance of
financial planning because you can't
really predict when these things will
happen and all that so the best thing to
help ourselves and our families is to do
proper disciplined financial
[Music]
planning as a life insurance company our
Solutions and the partnership uh that we
want to establish with our stakeholders
as well as our policy holders is one
that is of a very long-term in nature
right so not shortterm not tactical not
not just for the one year two years of
five years we really want a very
long-term relationship and in that
regard I think again based on the depth
of the market or the the regulations and
how how each country function is at
different stages right so and of course
there are clear key learnings so from
that perspective be it a platform play
be it a uh SG fex for example in in a
more mature uh scenario like in
Singapore we see the benefits of it we
see the customers really logging in
really One Touch of the button from that
perspective having that Consolidated
View and that helps us as we continue to
manage those conversations with them in
financial planning not just having a
sliced view but a holistic View and and
that that is very very
[Music]
powerful we see the beauty of taking
insurance or / health and technology and
putting these two together to better
serve our customers so some key examples
will be
say say your health insurance right
health insurance that you that that the
customers purchase and then there will
be a yearly premium that that will be
payable so we
employ AI talkbot right AI talkbot in a
very friendly way to remind the
customers in terms of the premium
payment it really understands the
empathy understanding the the tone of
the customers and then speaking in the
local local language so to speak right
so this this helps us in in making sure
that our customers continue to be
protected okay right because if the
policy is laps or is canceled then it's
going to be something that's unu to the
policy holder of the family so this is
one example of using in the health area
together with technology another key
thing that we have seen is
actually tell
medical services that we provide Beyond
just the T medine but this is also using
the t uh platform to really do Health
examination right traditionally some
some cases will require our applicants
or policy holders to go see a doctor
from what we see in the data some may
take two to four weeks right depending
again on the availability of the policy
holder themselves or with the medical
provider right to to fix an appointment
and even when they go there they may be
subject to some weight time and the
actual session may take right again
depending right half an hour 1 hour or
Beyond so what we have done is actually
understanding the customers paino and
the feedback and looking at technology
that's available so in short we deployed
this on a t basis M so from a tally
perspective the our applicants can go
through that so in the comfort of say
their home or their offices right then
the the doctor will be seeing them via
the tally so the the time is compressed
is fast is convenient there's no weight
time and the entire process is fast
thereafter we as a company will get
those records or get those uh
confirmation from the medical provider
and then we can then process on the
entire
[Music]
transaction there are differences but at
the same time there are also
similarities so so if you reference you
know uh consumer banking wealth
management right so I equate
that and
insurance being quite similar the the
overlap is actually very very large in
the sense of both models in my mind it
uses a large Salesforce in terms of
number of people to serve a large
customer
base with Financial Solutions and underg
GED by digital capabilities so these
four things right large customer base
large Salesforce Financial Solutions
digital is pervasive in the consumer
banking space as well as the insurance
space however your other point earlier
that you mentioned is also true because
traditionally for insurance if if it's
for example specifically done more true
agency in the past then those touches
with the customer may be only that few
times a year year whereas compared to a
bank right because Banking and again
right with with technology with the
different uh Services there are more
touches with the bank in the sense of
your savings checking account your pay
now your credit card transaction
payments is is literally daily in that
sense but however from an insurance
company perspective for for credential
in specific we are also moving and using
let's say a very important Area Health
Insurance Healthcare needs right right
of of the customer base that is fast
changing right and we are also changing
our our thinking in terms of in the past
just being a payer right that means if
the client in the past just bought a
health insurance with us and that is
touchwood but it's only at the untoward
circumstance right maybe when they fall
sick get hospitalized on that then they
will activate the policy and then submit
a claim but that is fast changing for us
because we are seeing now with with
progress of technology and and in the
digital space that we want to move from
just being a payer to being a partner
with our policy holders and how we do
that is through connected care how we do
that is through adding a lot more value
to the to the policy holder instead of
just purely in those unfortunate
situation then it's just pain so
partnering you with your health Journey
throughout and that gives us a lot more
opportunities to touch base to
communicate to engage our policy holders
so in that in that sense that is fast
changing maybe not as as instant as you
know every down to the every second of
payment like a banking system but
definitely compared to a very
traditional Insurance approach of just
selling and then after that maybe a
yearly review or only during claims
right at at uh demise of a family or or
accidents or disability right very unow
situation we now have a lot more time
just because again from payer to being a
[Music]
partner traditionally right as an
insurance company for applications that
come in obviously we will then go
through one additional step which you
may not really see say in the other
parts of the banking or the financial
services industry right so for us
uniquely in insurance we need to do
underwriting MH so that could be time
consuming laborious in the past m not so
now so for example in credential
Singapore up to 75% of our cases that
come true the business that comes true
goes through what we call Auto
underwriting that means automatic
underwrite that means the whole engine
the whole parameter leveraging on
technology that has been built and
refined over the over the recent years
to a to a space now whereby
75% is Auto underwritten auto
underwriting means the benefit to you is
to to the advisor they they get a
instant yeah instant they will know
whether after this Auto underwriting
case is to be incepted or not right or
to be rejected so that gives our
Frontline advisers U information faster
it also then gives peace of mind and
also faster response to the applicant M
um and not only just the application
once is approved within a couple hours
you get all your e policy right in the
past is is is very thick it's it's
complex and all that you get it snail me
so it cut now from a customer experience
in the past is days now is
literally minutes or a couple hours
depending on the complexity so I think
these are some of the beauty of again
harnessing technology to do all these
things that is quite complex behind the
scenes right from underwriting process
to make it now as seamless and as
venient to all the
[Music]
stakeholders I
think technology of course is a very
broad right word but in specific I would
say data
analytics
AI right machine learning these fields
will continue to gather Pace very
quickly so the changes that come right
um the n bonness that companies need to
be right to harness that and of course
to understand the risk and then how do
we how do we manage that because it
needs also that accuracy the the
Assurance to the public to the
individuals concern to the individual
policy holders and we as a company we
want to get that right 100% of the time
as well but yet that is a fast growing
space so I see back to your point I
think that is the fast growing Trend and
we are writing that Trend so it's
important that our employees our fellow
colleagues really understand AI That's
why we are rolling out different
programs right machine learning even I
myself also went through that right to
make sure that all of we want to support
and enable our Workforce to really
understand these new things and then how
does it apply to their individual
[Music]
jobs so clearly insurance we are in it
for the long haul M very very long-term
relationship I always talk about earlier
and and it's important that we Safeguard
the interest of our policy holders not
just for the here and now but for a
long-term perspective so while we
harness the power of digital technology
for for business generation for sales
for servicing at the same time we are
also harnessing all of that from a risk
management perspective right because
ultimately what is insurance insurance
is all about risk management so we
continue to harness the the best of what
technology brings to us and to the world
to be able to use that for detection
purposes right for for all the different
processes at the backend that we do so
happy to say that in Singapore this is a
is definitely evolving space but this is
something that we continuously focus on
and the retention rate the
persistency of not just us but as a
industry here in Singapore for life
insurance is extremely high and and with
the fraud uh and and and those kind of
incidents being very very low and
[Music]
minimal I'm personally very proud and uh
honored to be associated with a company
that work in that is so deep in this
area so specifically for credential
Singapore um the Singapore team already
six to almost 7 years ago already have
had a hit of sustainability and the team
Focus in this area right we have also
recently published our F fifth uh
voluntarily published annual
sustainability report so that is the
kind of maturity here locally in
Singapore but now from a group
perspective likewise right prenal group
is very very focused on sustainability
so in specific some of the things that
we' have been doing are a few Falls
right one clearly making sure that
health and financial protection
is accessible to the community and to
our customers and we do that through
many many different ways right so the co
period like we talked about earlier Co
period of Us coming out with bite-size
products making it accessible to people
uh or Co related products back then in
Singapore right
Deni seasonality right so again we have
a bze micro insurance for dingi things
like that to make it very simple and
accessible to people right so there's
one example we have also launched ESG
climate right Global impact kind of a
ESG themed uh products as well to the
marketplace so that's another another
thing that will make it easy and
[Music]
accessible absolutely we see micro
Insurance uh right it's not just here in
Singapore but in the recent years we and
probably arguably I would say even more
pervasive the Emerging Markets because
uh the reach is just amazing right I
mean Singapore here yes right is a very
uh it's more affluent market right it's
more established so average tickets
tends to be higher but in those populous
countries the bike size the the the
simple easy access to insurance that
kind of platform is is very important so
we continue to see that as well but
earlier to your point other than just
supporting the whole ESG and and
sustainability agenda with customer
facing products that's one but
importantly what we do is also
responsible investment and that to me in
the short term my personal view is that
that will have a even greater impact
what do I mean by that right so as an
insurance company we obviously
manufacture Solutions and we Avail that
when the clients take on those policies
for protection Whole Life policies or
even for wealth and investment Purp
verus the monies that we collect the not
the millions but the not just the
billions but the tens of billions of
dollars that we collect we wouldn't
invest in those so imagine if now that
we have a very we have a very strong ESG
sustainability lens over that that gives
us a very very quick and uh of course we
are responsible and we want to use that
platform focusing on responsible
Investments to really do good from that
perspective so maybe a couple of
examples of what we have done as a
company regionally what we have done is
we have divested from companies that
means the Investments we have divested
from companies that derive more than 30%
of their income from coal so that's one
key step the other one is to really
continuously focus on the what we call
right what the industry calls the wacky
weighted average carbon intensity so we
have committed to reducing 55% of the
wacki in our whole Investment Portfolio
and we are on track to doing that the
55% Target is not a 2050 right we always
say 2050 Net Zero and all that even us
as a company we are pledged that but the
wacky reduction of the 55% is by
2030 in the next few years and we are
already on track to achieving that so
these are some of the examples of us
being a responsible investor so to speak
and final point is that of course then
the rest of it is sustainable business
internally right so working with our
Workforce to make sure that we support
them in their daily work to understand
the environmental impact the um
workplace and health uh safety Health in
the workplace in the work office
environment so these are all the
different things that we' been
supporting to towards the sustainability
agenda
[Music]
I get asked this question a lot right so
it's always the banking why did I move
from banking to to Insurance my real
story is this right so it's lesser of
banking to Insurance my own personal
story is more of already semi Insurance
why don't I go fulltime Insurance
because when I first joined so-call
banking my first job after school was
actually insurance I was doing insurance
work but in the banking environment I
was an insurance product manager then in
you know in the year in the early 2000s
in Singapore right when the high netw
worth Insurance space was fast taking
off I was part back then part of uh the
front line I was working at the front
working with my sales sales colleagues
my service colleagues to really help
singaporeans to really help individuals
and families affluent segment right and
the high Networth segment to really
embed Insurance very very strongly into
their whole financial planning and of
course then in my last 10 years in my
previous uh company whereby it was a
banking group that owns an insurance
company I saw how insurance was kind of
manage as as a holistic business and how
it will impact people so there in lies
my story so it's lesser of banking to
insurance but it really I was in
insurance work I have now decided to
dedicate the the the the Final Chapter
so to speak of my career to be very
focused in really helping individuals
and families and and really focusing in
this very deep Insurance vertical as
opposed to banking previously was great
doing some insurance work but it it's
more breath so this is this is my
commitment to really um using Insurance
to better serve the
[Music]
community of course there's one thing
that is a bit different in the insurance
industry compared to Pure banking or
consumer banking is the is the
Relentless focus on protection and
health right so that that is more I see
that doing a lot more in this space and
that's the opportunity to work with our
banking Partners right and and and
ecosystem Partners alike to really
further that agenda ultimately this is
this is also a national agenda right so
the healthc care the the rising
healthare cost and the inflation how do
we kind of address some of these things
right and these are very real not just
in Singapore but we see it in the region
and is also a global Trend so I think
that's some of the things that I'm
seeing happening and that is purposeful
and meaningful for us to tackle that's
how I feel that as a business we can
have the maximum uh positive impact on
the community that we serve
[Music]